

Artem Petrov

Software Developer / Data Scientist

□ artem343p@gmail.com

St. Petersburg, Russia (happy to relocate)

in linkedin.com/in/artem343

github.com/artem343



artempetrov.work

CAREER SUMMARY

I am a software developer with a degree in information systems. After working as a web developer for a while, I took a break from software engineering and worked as an interpreter and translator, specializing in international politics. Now I'm coming back with determination and several Python pet projects from the realm of data science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

T-Systems

2014 - 2015

Developed a navigation system that helped employees easily locate each other in the offices.

Regular business trips to Germany, teleconferencing with German colleagues.

Technologies used:

Ruby on Rails

HTML/CSS

jQuery

MySQL

Translator

United Nations

2016 - 2020

Translating verbatim reports of United Nations General Assembly, Security Council and other principal bodies. Enhancing translation memory databases.

Technologies used:

brain keyboard dictionaries

machine translation

PROJECTS

YouTube Trends Analyzer

Using trending videos by country provided by YouTube API to plot viewers' recent preferences on the world map.

Technologies used:

pandas flask folium GeoJSON

YouTube API

Movie Recommender

Using the MovieLens dataset to train a collaborative filtering recommender model (based on cosine similarity) and suggest movies to the users.

Technologies used:

pandas Django PostgreSQL

collab. filtering

Twitter Sentiment Analyzer

Periodically grabbing latest tweets by keywords and announcing their average sentiment on a Google Home speaker.

Technologies used:

Docker | MongoDB | Google API

Slack API

Twitter API

SKILLS & TOOLS

Data Science

St. Petersburg

New York / remote

pandas, scikit-learn, Jupyter

PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite

BeautifulSoup, scrapy, regex

Keras, NLP, NoSQL, metabase

General

Python, Flask, Django

HTML/CSS

docker, AWS

Others

bash APIs heroku cron

EDUCATION

Data Science

SPICED Academy

Berlin

Dip. Information Systems

ITMO University

St. Petersburg, Russia 2010 - 2015

PgDip. Conference Interpreting and Translation

School of Interpretation and Translation

St. Petersburg, Russia 2015 - 2016

LANGUAGES

Russian (Native)

English (Professional)

German (Professional)

Polish (Professional)